The credit for today's video goes to the comment of this gentleman.
Thank you for your comment sir.  As you all know
that every day every video on the channel comes
according to your questions, suggestions and comments.
So stay connected to the channel and
like the video for that, you have already liked it
, share it.  Subscribe to the channel and turn
on all the notification bells
because only through that you can get the videos on time.
Hello everyone,
you all are very welcome.  You're watching You the Real.
I am your personal advisor Amit Raj
Sharma.  In today's video, we are learning about ICICI
Potential Life's Smart Insurance
Plan Plus, which you also know as Smart SIP Plus.
This plan is a non-participating
linked individual savings life insurance
plan.  There are two different variants in this plan.
The first is the Wealth variant, the
second is the Ashore variant.  Along with this, the plan has
26 different fund options and you also get the
option of four different portfolio strategies.  At the
time of purchasing the plan,
you choose the plan variant,
portfolio strategy, fund
option and decide the cover amount.
Decide the policy term and
pay the premium to the insurance company.
Now since this is a linked plan, the
insurance company invests the premium in the market through the fund chosen by you.  On
which there is risk through out the
policy term and the responsibility for that risk is
solely yours.
As soon as the policy term is completed,
you get the fund value as a
maturity benefit.  If
something happens to you during the policy term, the
death benefit on the selected variant is
passed on to your nominee.  We will understand the benefits further.
Now we will first learn about ICICI
Pharma Life's Smart Insurance Plan
Plus i.e. Smart SIP Plus
portfolio option.  The first is the
fixed portfolio strategy in which
you choose the fund options as per your wish
and decide
how much money should be invested in which fund.  You
can do this manually or you
can opt for an automatic transfer strategy in which the money will be automatically transferred to the funds you
select in the same
ratio.  If you do it manually,
you will get unlimited free switches.
You will also be able to redirect premium
from one fund to another.  But the
minimum value of switches should be at least ₹2000.
If it is less than that then you will
not be able to do unlimited switches here.
Right?  The second option is the target asset
allocation strategy.  The name of Target Asset Allocation
Strategy itself suggests that
you have chosen the fund option as per your risk appetite, that is, the
amount of risk you can take for a plan
term,
and accordingly you have decided the premium
that there will be so much proposition in equity
and so much in debt or
whatever you decide in equity, accordingly
your premium should be invested in the same fund
through the policy term.
ok sir?  Because it will be targeted.
You target one fund, two funds
, three funds, as many as you want, the
money will keep going into them.  The third option
here is life cycle based
portfolio strategy.  In this
you get a combination of equity and debt.  The
equity oriented fund is Multicap
Growth Fund.  If your age at the time of taking the plan is
up to 25 years, then 80% of the
portfolio will be in equity
i.e. in multicap growth fund.  20% will
remain in the income fund i.e. day fund.
If the age is between 36 to 45 years
then 65% should be invested in equity and 35% in income fund
i.e. debt.  That means where is 65%
living?  In Multicap Growth Fund which is an
equity oriented fund.  It is a high risk
category fund.  35% within the income fund.
The age percentage on rest s is given here.
You can pause and read it.  The last option
is your Tigard Portfolio Strategy
option.  Here, Multicap Growth Fund, which is an
equity based fund right, will have 75%
of your premium in the overall portfolio
and 25% will remain in the Income Fund,
this ratio will be maintained through the policy term.
Now let's say you chose the trigger event as
10%.  That means, if there is a growth of 10% in equity, then the
increased percentage of
profit will be automatically transferred by the company to the income fund
and this will continue through
out the policy term so that the
gain on your equity is
transferred to debt.  What
are the fund options now?  There are 26 fund options.  If I
tell the details of each fund one by one, it will
take at least 3 minutes to tell the details of one fund.
Right?  So for this reason I am writing the names of the funds here on
top of your screen.
You can pause them and read them.
If you tell me the name of the fund you
want to know about, I will bring a separate video.
Ok?  All these fund
options on the screen are in the high risk
category.  Due to this, a fund management charge of
1.35% of the annual average fund value will be levied.
Right?  The names of the
fund stocks in the mid-cap category are also displayed on the
top of your screen.  These also belong to the high
risk category.  Along with this, there
is also a multicap fund which you call large, mid and
small cap fund.  Right?  Their
information is at the top of your screen.  Pause and
read it.  These too fall in the high risk category, so
they too will attract a fund management charge of 1.35% of the annual average fund value
every year.  There are
also balanced funds like Multicap
Balanced Active Asset Allocation Balanced Fund which
fall in the medium risk category.
Balance is an advantage fund.  It is a mid-cap hybrid
growth fund.  This is a high risk category
fund.  The names of debt oriented funds are
Secure Opportunities Fund, Income Fund, Money
Market Fund, all these are low risk category
funds.  In money market funds only, fund management charges of
0.75% of the annual average fund value will be levied.  For all others, a
fund management charge of 1.35% of the average fund value per annum will be levied.  Pause and read the
names of all the funds.  Tell us in the comment section
which fund you want to know about.
You will get its video separately.
Ok?  Let us now know about the eligibility criteria of ICICI
Prudential Life's Smart Insurance Plan
Plus
and first of all, let us know about its Wealth
variant.  The
age limit for taking this variant is from zero to
50 years.  That means if you have a newborn baby,
you will be able to take this plan for him also.   The
premium payment term is available for a minimum of 5 years and a maximum of
15 years.  The
minimum premium limit in the Wealth variant is ₹12,000.
If your age is 35 years or
less than 35 years at the time of taking the plan.  If the age is up to 36 years or 50
years, then the minimum annual premium to be
paid is ₹1,20,000.  The maturity age
limit is 18 to 75 years.  This means that one will be able to remain
under cover till the maximum age of 75 years.  Let's
talk about the policy term.  If
your annual premium is less than ₹6 lakh, then
subtract your age from 75.   The
minimum policy term will be exhausted.  If
your annual premium is ₹6 lakh or
more, then you can get a policy term of 15 years
here.
To calculate the maximum policy term,
you will subtract 75, that is, your age at the time of purchasing the plan, from 75.  There are
mainly two benefits in the Wealth variant.  The first
is the death benefit which will be withdrawn by
comparing the sum assured with the fund value.
Then the minimum death benefit
in the plan which is 105% of the total premium paid will be
compared with that.
Whichever is higher of these three will be
given as death benefit to the nominee and the policy will be closed.
As soon as the maturity comes, that is,
if the policy term is completed, then the
market value of all the units, which we
call fund value, will be given to you at the time of
maturity and the
policy will be terminated.
You can also avail the maturity benefit in installments.
An example of the Wealth variant is given in the policy brochure.  We will talk about that only.  Let us
assume that the gentleman is
30 years old.  He has opted for
Smart
Insurance Plan Plus i.e. Smart
SIV Plus Plan of ICICI Potential Life Insurance Company Limited
with Wealth Variant. He has taken policy term of
45 years and premium payment term of
10 years.  Sum Assured is
10 times the annual premium i.e. he took ₹1 lakh.
He is paying a premium of ₹1 lakh annually.  The
fund option he has chosen
is Maximizer Fifth which is an equity
oriented fund.  Now, if he
dies within the premium payment term, the life
insurance will be worth ₹1 lakh.  That nominee gets at
least the minimum death benefit.  At the same time,
if the premium payment term is completed, then
we withdraw 105% of the total pay which becomes
₹1500.  This is the minimum death benefit.
Okay, right?  And if he survives till the age of 45 years, that is, he has
completed the policy term of 15 years, then the
policy brochure says here that
if the rate of return is 8% at the age of 45 years, then
he can get an amount around ₹1 crore 199 lakh.  That means
if ₹19143744 remains at 4% then
they can get ₹255486.  It is just an
example.  Now we will learn about the
eligibility criteria of the second variant
i.e. the Ashor variant.  The
age limit for taking the Ashor variant is
from 18 years to 40 years.
And the minimum or
maximum maturity age limit here is 33
to 60 years.  That means he will remain
under cover till at least the age of 33.  You
can remain under the cover till the maximum age of 60 years.   The
minimum premium limit is
₹12,000 per year.  If the
age at the time of taking the plan is up to 35 years, then the minimum
premium payment term is 5 years.  If the age is
more than 35 years then the minimum
premium payment term will be 6 years.  The maximum
premium payment term is
15 years with the assured variant.  When it comes to
policy term, you can
take a policy term of at least 15 years.  Maximum 25 years old.
Talking about the basic understanding,
you can get anywhere from seven times to 10 times the annual premium.
With both variants.  If you are paying top-up premium, you can
get life cover up to 10 times the top-up premium.  If the
insurance company allows, the minimum
top-up premium limit for both
variants is ₹500.  ICICI
Pashul L's smart insurance plan is
also
known as Smart SIV Plus Plan.  Talking about the benefits of its Ashor variant, it
is the same.  If the policy term is
completed, you will get the fund value
which you can also take in installments.
The difference will be in the death benefit.  If the
policyholder dies within the policy term
and the premium payment term has
not been completed, then lump sum death claim benefit will be
available.  After that you will get smart benefits.  The
smart benefit will be that the
company itself will fund all the future premiums which were to be
paid within the premium payment term.  The
percentage of family income benefit is up to
10% of the sum earned.  The nominee will continue to receive it every year.
And as soon as the policy
term is completed, then at the end you will
also get the fund value i.e. you will
also get the maturity benefit.  So this is the difference between
both the variants.  The example
given in the policy brochure is Mr.
Nishant ji, who is 30 years old.
He took
Smart Insurance
Plan Plus i.e. Smart SIB Plus
Plan of ICICI Pt. Life Insurance Company Limited.  He is paying a premium of ₹1 lakh annually.
Taking a policy term of 25 years.
Taking a premium payment term of 10 years.  And
he has chosen the rate of family income benefit as 10%
and is
investing the money in Maximizer Fifth i.e. equity oriented fund.  So
according to the policy brochure available on the company's website, if the return is 8%
then
they will get an amount of around ₹31,48,000.  Otherwise you will get it for
around ₹13,70,000.  Right?
Suppose Mr. Ishan dies
after completion of 5 years of the policy, then
his nominee will get the amount of ₹1 lakh.
Right?  And the premium of ₹5 lakh that was to be paid for the next 5 years will be
funded by the company itself
and in the remaining 21 years of the policy, the
nominee will continue to receive ₹1 lakh every year.  You will
also get maturity benefits at the end.  According to whatever the market value will be.  Well,
here for
example, if its rate of return is 8%
then 34 lakhs is written here.   could be possible.  This will happen, but it is
not guaranteed
under the unit linked plan.
You people know this thing.  Now let's talk about the
charges here, see, premium allocation
charge will not be applicable in this.
I have already told you about the fund management charges that will be applicable.
Policy administration charges are
not applicable under this plan.  Motility charges apply.
Depends on the variant.  If you
choose Wealth variant, the rate will be different.  If
you choose the Assured variant, separate charges will be applicable.
What is the policy term with this?
How much cover amount are you taking?  How is your health?
What is your age?  These
charges will depend on the extras.
When will the policy discontinuance charge be applicable?  If
you discontinue the policy within the first four years, the maximum
penalty can range from ₹1000 to ₹6000.  If you are
discontinuing the policy after the fifth year, then
you do not have to pay policy discontinuance charges.
Ok?
When will I receive my parcel withdrawal?  When the first 5 years are completed
and you are required to be 18 years old at the time of parcel withdrawal.  The
minimum partial
withdrawal is ₹2000.  The maximum parcel
withdrawal you can make within a year is up
to 20% of your fund value.  But
after partial withdrawal, the FB i.e.
fund balance should be at least three times your annual premium.  The
second
option is Systematic Withdrawal
Plan.  If you are opting for systematic withdrawal, then
in this also the age should be 18 years
at the time of withdrawal and the
locking period i.e. first 5 years should be completed only then
it is applicable.  The limit is the
same, maximum you can
get up to 20% of your fund value within a year.   I am
mentioning this limit here in the policy brochure.  It is written in it that the
FB i.e. the fund balance should also be
three times the annual premium
after the withdrawal.  Ok?   The
minimum withdrawal amount is also the same.  Like it was mentioned
in the parcel withdrawal that it was worth ₹2000.   The
remaining ratio is that you can select
how much of your fund value you want every year, from 1% to 20%.
Right?  If these criteria are fulfilled then
you will get systematic withdrawal.
Free look up period is available within the plan.  On the
date you received the policy bond, you checked the
policy bond and
you do not agree with the details and conditions written in it.
You feel that you were given the
plan after telling you something else.  Something else is
written in it.  So you can cancel
your policy within 30 days from the date on which you received the documents.  You
can get a refund.  Along with
this, if you have chosen the Wealth variant, then
when 2 months are left in the premium payment term, you
can extend your premium payment term.  This was the
detail of this plan which has been shared with you on the
policy brochure.  There
are 26 fund options in the plan and it takes at least
3 minutes to explain about one fund.  Because of this,
I leave it to you to share the details about the
funds you would like to know about.
Please
write the name of the fund in the comment section.  Please do
like and share the video.
Happy New Year to all of you.  All of you should take
care of yourself and do
your financial planning before taking the Unlink plan.
Otherwise there is no use